<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Computational Biology Portfolio</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on My Computational Biology Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Diving into R and Python</title>
      <link>/post/2021/05/07/diving-into-r-and-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021/05/07/diving-into-r-and-python/</guid>
      <description>The majority of this computational biology course has focused on programming language R, the language of statistics. We started off with data visualization, which included probability and plotting distributions. Next, we slipped into DPLYR so that we could learn to construct more elegant-looking tables and graphs. With DPLYR under our belts, we experimented with wrangling and tidying data to make it easier to work with. The results of this first unit can be seen in Project 1 that explores the effect certain storm factors have on sea level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2</title>
      <link>/project/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project2/</guid>
      <description>knitr::opts_chunk$set(echo = TRUE, eval = TRUE, fig.align = &amp;quot;center&amp;quot;, warning = F, message = F, tidy = TRUE, tidy.opts = list(width.cutoff = 60), R.options = list(max.print = 100)) Kristina Rodrigues; UT EID: kpr484  Introduction Our earth is slowly changing due to our carbon footprint and global warming. This has resulted in more intense, harder-to-predict natural disasters that have been taking the world by storm. In my previous project, I looked at the at how different factors impacted the intensity of storms by looking at sealevel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project_1</title>
      <link>/project/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project1/</guid>
      <description>knitr::opts_chunk$set(echo = TRUE, eval = TRUE, fig.align = &amp;quot;center&amp;quot;, warning = F, message = F, tidy = TRUE, tidy.opts = list(width.cutoff = 60), R.options = list(max.print = 100)) Kristina Rodrigues; UT EID: kpr484 ###Introduction Climate change is becoming a hot topic these days with rising temperatures and concurrently an increase in tropical storms. The first dataset I chose focuses on different tropical storms and their characteristics: storm name, year, date of report, coordinates, pressure (in millibars), status, category, and wind speed (in knots).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description> Check out some of my coding projects below:
 Wrangling &amp;amp; Exploratory Data Analysis
 Modeling, Inference, Prediction
  -- </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
